[ gunshot ]
[ body thuds ]
The boat can leave now .
Tell the crew .
[ ship horn blowing in distance ]
[ creaking ]
[ ship horn blowing ]
[ blowing ]
- [ helicopter whirring ] - [ man ] Chopper 1 to Headquarters .
Chopper 1 to Headquarters . We got a sailboat on a collision course ...
with just about every boat in the harbor .
- [ man on radio ] Where 's it at , Chopper 1 ? - Just off Staten Island .
It was almost run down by the ferry .
We can 't raise anyone on board .
Okay , Chopper 1 . We 'll send out a patrol boat .
[ klaxon sounding , siren wailing ]
- That must be it , Bill . - Okay . We 'll take a look at her .
[ man in helicopter ] Chopper 1 to Headquarters .
The Harbor Patrol 's coming alongside the sailboat now .
[ voice amplified ] Ahoy there ! This is the Harbor Patrol .
Anyone on board ?
- [ siren wailing ] - Hey , Sarge , that boat 's abandoned .
Yeah , she looks abandoned .
The only question is , why ?
Hey , if she is , Marty ,
we stand to make a nice little bonus when we bring her in .
Yeah . Let 's get over there and check .
[ voice amplified ] Bring her up alongside .
[ man in helicopter ] Chopper 1 to Headquarters . Chopper 1 to Headquarters .
[ man on radio ] This is Headquarters . Come in , Chopper 1 .
The Harbor Patrol is about to board now . Still no sign of life .
Skipper of that craft must be a real turkey .
[ insects buzzing ]
[ Marty ] Hey , watch out for the sail !
Huh ? What ?
[ Bill ] ] what the hell 's going on ?
I 'm sorry . The winch is broken .
[ groans ] I 'll fix the sail .
- You go below and look around . - Okay .
[ insects buzzing ]
[ buzzing continues ]
[ squeaking ]
[ growling ]
[ gasping ]
[ Marty screaming ]
[ slurping ]
[ screaming ]
Don 't move .
Stay where you are , mister . Throw your hands on the deck there .
I told you not to move !
I mean it !
One more step , and I 'm gonna blast you . Now , freeze where you are .
Don 't move , I said .
- [ growling ] - Don 't move !
[ chattering ]
Yeah . Yeah . Where did they find this abandoned boat ?
Mm-hmm .
Yeah , I 'll put someone on it . The boys in blue been there yet ?
Thanks for the information . You 're a sweetheart .
Get West in here .
- I didn 't see — Hello , Jeff . - Peter , the chief wants you .
- Right . Thanks . See ya . - Uh-huh . Okay .
- What can I do for you , Chief ? - Sit down .
- Are you busy now , limey ? - Uh — That depends .
I 'm giving you an assignment .
Get over to — What did she say ? Ah .
Pier 15 . There 's a story there .
Is it something big ?
Hmm . Boat without anyone on it . Cop killed .
Poke around a bit . See what you can find . You know .
Okay . I 'll let you know .
Uh , West .
Keep the British out of your prose , huh ?
Don 't take advantage of the fact your uncle bought the paper .
As if I would .
[ camera shutter clicks ]
[ chattering ]
[ man ] The Harbor Patrol launch is leaving now .
What about the body ?
It 's down to the chief medical examiner 's office for the autopsy .
Lady , step back , will you , please ?
All right , back , back ! You there , back over there .
Come on ! Back through the gate . There 's nothing to see .
[ man ] Well , Miss Bowles , we 're waiting .
Yes . It 's my father 's boat .
Where 's your father now ?
I don 't know . Actually , I was hoping you could tell me .
I haven 't heard from him in over a month .
I see .
And how long since you last spoke to him ?
Uh , three months .
When he set sail for the Antilles to join some friends .
The Antilles ?
Will someone please tell me what the hell 's going on ?
We already have .
Man hiding on his boat — which was adrift — killed a member of the Coast Guard .
Yeah , but ... my father , where is he ?
I mean , what 's happened to him ?
That 's just what we 'd like to know , Miss Bowles .
[ siren wailing ]
Sorry to get you down here at this hour .
I really can 't understand why they 're in such a hurry .
I really can 't understand myself .
The D.A. 's office phoned twice before you arrived , Doc .
Well , let 's get it over with .
Have you — Have you already examined him ?
Yeah . I made one or two notes .
In my opinion ,
the death of the poor bastard was caused by a massive hemorrhage ...
due to a huge laceration of the jugular .
Hmm .
Do you have a hypothesis for the cause of this injury ?
Take a look at these edges .
To me it 's quite obvious what caused it .
There appear to be clear indications of one or more bites .
Look carefully .
Pass me the scalpel .
I wouldn 't be able to cut my way through tissue paper with that ,
let alone carry out an autopsy .
Take better care of your instruments , James .
Yes , Doctor .
[ police radio chatter ]
[ dispatcher , indistinct ]
[ chatter continues ]
[ disco playing ]
[ music continues ]
[ ship creaking ]
[ ship horn blowing ]
[ gasps ]
Don 't scream . Don 't scream .
There 's nothing to be afraid of .
My name is Peter West , and I 'm a reporter .
I 'm gonna take my hand away , and you 're not gonna scream , okay ?
- Mm-hmm . - Okay .
I 'm sorry if I frightened you .
But if I hadn 't done that , you 'd have screamed for sure ,
and our friend up there would have been onto both of us .
Who are you , and what are you doing on my father 's boat ?
I 've already told you . My name 's West , and I 'm a reporter .
I 've been following you all afternoon .
How clever . Professional curiosity ?
Well , the police version doesn 't convince me ,
and I guess it doesn 't convince you either .
Otherwise you wouldn 't be here .
What , uh — What were you looking for ?
You 've got a hell of a nerve , you know that ?
[ chuckles ] You 're not so bad yourself .
- Oh , please . - Let me put it this way .
I 've got some information . You 've got some information .
So why don 't we just throw it together and see what we can come up with ?
' Cause I think I 've already found what you 're looking for .
[ gasping ]
[ clattering ]
[ siren blares ]
[ ship horn blows ]
[ footsteps on deck ]
What do we do now ?
Well , I 've got an idea , but , uh , I 'm gonna need your help .
Unless , of course , you want to be explaining to some judge ...
what you were doing on board your father 's boat in the middle of the night .
Now , just do what I tell you , okay ?
- Okay . - Good . Come on .
[ woman moaning ]
[ policeman ] Hey , what the hell 's go —
[ Bowles ] Oh ! Oh .
On .
Don 't give me the same old story .
- Well , actually , Officer , uh — - Same old story , huh ?
This is all your fault . You realize that , don 't you ?
It was his idea , not mine .
Well , listen to her , Miss Goody Two-shoes .
- [ gasps ] - It wasn 't her fault . It was all my idea .
Well , whose idea was it to have a romantic setting down by the water ?
I 'd have settled for an empty boxcar .
Oh , no . Never again . Not another boxcar .
Yeah , well , she takes after her mother . They 're both bananas .
You leave my mother out of this !
- [ Peter ] She 's crazy , and you know it . - Enough of this .
- Both of you , get out of here . - Okay , Officer . Okay . Anything you say .
Come on , sweetie pie .
Good night , Officer .
Yeah . Out of my sight .
Good night .
" To my daughter Anne , in case anything should happen to me .
Due to my morbid curiosity , I have managed to contract a strange disease ,
and they 're taking care of me as if I were some sort of guinea pig .
But I know I 'll never leave this island again , at least not alive .
I haven 't been a good father , but I have always loved you . One last kiss from Dad . "
Matool . And it 's dated 15 September .
Listen , Chief . You know ,
I 'm sure there 's some connection that ties this all together .
Well , her father , the disease he mentions ,
the boat and the guy that got killed as well .
Yeah , well , it 's her idea to go .
Okay , Chief , fine .
Oh , yeah , and , Chief , you 'll , um - you 'll fix the tickets , okay ?
Thanks . You 're beautiful .
- I think it 's three hours . - Yeah .
If it 's on schedule , we should arrive in St. Thomas —
- [ woman on P.A. ] Flight 782 — - Was that us ?
for St. Thomas and the Dominican Republic . Passengers have time to —
Let 's go .
No , no , no , no , no . I 'll do it .
You lead the way , hmm ?
[ man on P.A. ] Transit service to Colorado Springs , Denver and Kansas City ,
ls now ready for immediate departure at Gate 4-B .
All aboard , please . This is your final call .
[ woman on P.A. ] John Berry , dial 228 . John Berry , dial 228 .
[ jet engine roaring ]
Do you wanna check on the boat first or shall we go straight to the hotel ?
I don 't know . Whatever you think .
Senor , do you know anyone who can rent us a boat ?
Boat , señor ?
I 'm sorry . Not easy here to find boat .
We want to go to Matool . It 's very important .
I 'm willing to pay whatever it costs .
Just now I remember something , señor .
This morning , a friend of mine , he say ...
two Americans , they cruise the islands .
That 's his boat .
Last one at edge of jetty .
Maybe they take you . You ask .
- Fine . - Gracias .
Thanks .
Pedro not help you good , señor ?
Oh , sure . Yes .
- There you are . Thanks again . - Gracias . Gracias .
Extra water . Store it in the galley .
Aye , aye , sir .
Ahoy there .
Hi .
- Hi yourself . - Hi . How you doing ?
I am Peter West , and this is Anne Bowles .
Susan Barrett .
And you 're talking to Brian Hull .
You wouldn 't be looking for a boat ride ?
We would . We hear you 're going on a tour of the islands .
Yeah , a little cruise . Two months of fishing , bathing and sunshine .
Well , we have to go to Matool .
We 're trying to locate Anne 's father .
She hasn 't heard from him for some time .
Matool .
That 's not a cool place to head .
Natives claim it 's cursed . They avoid it like the plague .
We have to go there all the same .
And you want a ride from us .
If that 's possible .
Any experience with boats ?
Uh-huh .
And the lady ?
I was born on a boat .
Okay , Peter .
We 'll have to load more supplies . You pay your share .
- Deal ? - A deal .
Step on board . Here .
Look , I 'll warn you right now .
Don 't expect us to come sightseeing once we get there .
I found it never pays to ignore native superstitions .
[ drumming in distance ]
[ radio static , beeps ]
This is Matool , calling Guadalupa 1 .
Matool calling Guadalupa 1 .
Come in , Guadalupa .
[ static ]
This is Dr. Menard calling Guadalupa 1 .
Menard calling Guadalupa 1 .
Come in , Guadalupa 1 .
Still no luck ?
No . I ...
I 'm afraid it 's useless to go on trying .
Then we 're cut off from the rest of the world .
Well , not hardly .
No , darling , I wouldn 't say that .
I want to leave this damn island , right now .
Well , you can 't right now .
The radio isn 't working .
How convenient for you .
I wouldn 't be surprised if you broke it on purpose .
You 're tired .
Go to hell !
[ sighs ]
David .
- Are you going out ? - I have to go to the hospital .
Have they found another one ?
They have , haven 't they ?
- Tell the truth . - Now , calm down .
Where did they find it this time ?
You really mustn 't drink so much , my darling .
I asked you a question .
They 're on the other side of the island .
When will they reach this side ? Tell me .
Now I really think you ought to rest . we 'll talk about it later .
There 's really no need to agitate yourself so much .
I hate you .
No .
You don 't know what you 're saying .
Oh , you 'd like to be able to pass me off as crazy .
Apart from — from a handful of superstitious natives ,
I 'm the only one who knows what you 're doing .
And don 't think I 'm going to keep my mouth shut .
I 'm going to tell everyone ...
that you 're the one who 's crazy ,
demented , cruel , evil -
[ gasps ]
I 'll be at the hospital .
[ chuckling ]
Hospital .
You still see yourself as the scientist you once were , don 't you ?
Well , you 're-you 're not .
You 're no better than one of their witch doctors .
Just stop it !
- My research is — - Research ! [ laughs ]
You call fooling around with superstitions and voodoo rites research ?
You know perfectly well that the work I 'm doing is very important .
- And I wouldn 't be here if it wasn 't ! - I don 't give a damn !
I don 't want to stay on this island one more hour .
Yet you won 't be happy until I meet one of your zombies .
Now , look ,
as soon as I 've understood the phenomenon , we 'll leave .
I don 't believe you . [ sobs ]
I don 't believe you .
I don 't believe anything you say anymore !
[ sobbing ]
[ mutters ]
[ wind whistling ]
[ door slams ]
[ drumming continues ]
Miguel .
- Sí , señor ? - I have to go to the hospital .
So make sure nobody comes near the house , all right ?
Sí , señor . Miguel guard . Doctor no worry .
- Nobody . - Sí , señor .
[ wind howling ]
[ engine starts ]
[ drumming in distance ]
- We sure were lucky to find you two . - You can say that .
We 're sure not having the same kind of luck trying to find your island for you .
We should be somewhere around here , right ?
More or less , yeah .
But according to the map ,
there are no islands for the next 50 miles .
Not necessarily true .
So many islands around here , that a lot have never even been charted .
Like the last couple we saw . They 're not on any chart . It 's all hit-and-miss .
- We could spend a month out here . - Like looking for a needle in a haystack .
- You don 't want to go back , do you ? - No , no , no .
No , we 'll find Matool . That 's a promise .
Hey , now , look , don 't go counting on us forever .
Don 't forget . We 're on vacation .
[ Susan ] Brian .
Let 's stop for a while . I wanna take some shots . How about it ?
Come on . It looks fantastic down below .
Okay .
[ spitting ]
[ shutter clicks ]
Look ! Over there .
See ?
[ Brian ] Yeah . That 's another island .
[ Peter ] Maybe we 're in luck at last .
Who 's to say that that isn 't Matool ?
Brian , help !
There 's a shark ! Help !
- Christ ! It 's gonna attack her . - [ Susan ] Hurry !
I 'm going back down !
[ rifle cocks ]
[ gunshots ]
- [ loud thud ] - [ grunts ]
[ bones cracking ]
[ gasping ]
- There was a man down there . - What ?
- There was a man . - A man ?
[ wind howling ]
[ insects buzzing ]
[ patients groaning ]
He 's over here , Doctor .
[ woman cries out ]
[ buzzing continues ]
[ groaning continues ]
I don 't think he 'll last till the morning .
What shall I do ?
Take him into the sacristy .
I don 't want the others to see him . There 's no need to alarm them .
Tie him down securely .
Doctor ! Doc !
Doctor , everybody — everybody leaving now .
Quiet . Quiet , please .
Nurse , look after that patient .
Doctor , the natives leaving village .
Everybody go . What do we do ?
Huh ?
Talk about it outside .
[ drumming in distance ]
- Well , what happened ? - I don 't know .
Here in village is great trouble and commotion .
It 's the juju man . The new one .
He 's speaking plenty . He seem to be possessed by all the devils in hell .
How ridiculous .
Doctor , the natives are plain crazy .
They run all over village .
They pick up their possessions . They disappear .
Where did they go ?
They 're going inland .
- They 're making voodoo , I think . - Voodoo .
- Voodoo won 't solve anything . - But , Doctor —
They 're afraid . They are much afraid , these people .
You too .
You 're afraid , aren 't you , Lucas ?
[ wind howling ]
[ heavy breathing ]
[ breathing continues ]
[ rustling ]
[ dog growling ]
[ breathing continues ]
[ dog whines ]
[ bird twitters ]
[ sighs ]
[ window squeaking ]
[ water stops running ]
[ sighs ]
[ rustling ]
[ gasping ]
[ door thudding ]
[ grunts , gasps ]
[ woman grunting ]
- [ door thudding ] - [ bones crunching ]
[ lock clicks ]
[ clattering ]
[ banging ]
[ grunting ]
[ panting ]
- [ growling ] - [ screaming ]
[ screaming continues ]
[ screaming ]
[ screaming intensifies ]
[ heavy breathing ]
[ wind howling ]
[ engine idling ]
[ Peter ] This is all right , Brian .
Give her two or three feet of slack and then tie her up .
Doctor . Dr. Menard .
What ?
What 's wrong ?
Matthias .
Matthias ? Matthias what ?
He 's —
Oh , why don 't you say it ? You afraid to say it ? Huh ?
It 's not that . I don 't believe in voodoo .
No , I don 't believe in voodoo either , but the natives around here do , so —
So we investigate the phenomena , right ?
I 've seen them , and you 've seen them .
Now Matthias , he 's one of them , is he ?
Yeah . Huh .
Well , we have to help him . We have to try to help him .
So we go to the hospital . Come on .
The driveshaft 's cracked . It must have been the shark when he hit us .
- Is it serious ? - Well , we have two possibilities .
Either we go ashore and walk around until we come to the local repair shop , or —
Or ?
Or we remain here , fire off a few flares ,
and hope that somebody will come and help us .
We 'll have a tough time making it to the next island ...
if we don 't get that shaft fixed .
Poor Matthias .
[ flare whistling ]
[ insects buzzing ]
- [ drumming in distance ] - [ natives chanting in distance ]
Let 's go .
- [ gunshot ] - [ whistling ]
- [ drumming continues ] - [ chanting continues ]
Doctor . Doctor .
- What is it , Lucas ? - Rockets .
There 's somebody firing rockets .
- Rockets ? - I seen them , man .
Do you know where they come from ?
Yes . They 're comin ' from Catfish Bay .
I 'd better go and investigate .
Take care of him for me , Nurse .
Who is it ? The devil ?
We 'll know soon enough . Come on . Let 's get this over with .
- [ drumming continues ] - [ chanting continues ]
- [ drumming grows louder ] - [ chanting grows louder ]
Bury them now , missy ?
No , not yet . There are two more who are going to die soon .
- [ woman ] Help me . - [ sobbing ]
- [ muttering ] - [ man groans ]
[ muttering ]
[ speaking Spanish ]
Mío Manuel .
[ gasps ]
Manuel !
Mí corazón .
I buried you . But I see you walking .
[ sobs ]
[ drumming ]
[ Menard ] I met your father about three years ago ...
when he first came out to these islands .
Whenever he could , he would come and stay for a few weeks here with me on —
On Matool .
When he ...
became a victim of the disease ...
he insisted upon staying , in spite of everything I said to him .
I insisted that he should leave , but he wouldn 't .
He felt that he could , in some way , become a guinea pig .
That he could help in discovering
what was causing the horrors that were destroying our island ...
transforming it into a wasteland of terror .
Extremely courageous man .
I remember the day when my assistant came to tell me
that your father was dying .
- [ footsteps approaching ] - Doctor , your friend . Quickly .
- [ labored breathing ] - [ footsteps approaching ]
[ insects buzzing ]
David , closer .
Finished .
I feel I 'm about to die . I had a good life .
But I never thought it would end this way .
But I 've got two things to ask . Listen carefully .
They 're very important , my friend .
I 've written to my dear child .
And the letter , see that it gets to her .
And make sure that ... [ wheezes ]
my soul rests in everlasting peace .
[ wheezing ]
[ Menard 's voice ] I spent the day watching over his body .
But I knew that eventually I would have to find the courage to release him .
[ gasps ]
[ sighs ]
[ body thuds ]
The boat can leave now .
Tell the crew .
- [ squawking ] - [ drumming ]
What exactly did my father die of , Dr. Menard ?
And the boat 's crew ? What happened to them ?
Yes , Doctor .
What is all this about the dead coming back to life again
and having to be killed a second time ?
I mean , what the hell 's going on here ?
- You ever heard of voodoo ? - [ Brian ] Voodoo ?
Doctor , you got to be joking . That 's kid 's stuff .
I mean , voodoo is just plain superstitious horseshit .
Basically , it 's a mixture of two religions .
One Catholicism , brought here by the Spanish conquistadores ...
and two ... African tribal rites that were brought here by the slave trade .
Well , whatever it is , it makes the dead stand up and walk .
I 've seen it with my own eyes .
That 's impossible .
I know it 's impossible !
It 's happening . I 've seen it .
The natives say it 's ... something to do with voodoo .
Some evil witch doctor who creates these zombies .
But I 'm sure there 's a natural explanation .
And I 'm determined to find it .
[ drumming continues ]
Doctor . Doctor , something 's happened to Mr. Fritz .
Oh , what happened to him ?
No one told me .
Missy , she take a look .
Go inside .
Bad news ?
Oh . Fritz , a friend of mine ,
who happens to be the only other white man on the island ,
he 's — he 's had an accident .
Oh , we 've got him at the hospital . I 'm sure he 'll be all right .
- Well , is there anything that we can do ? - No , no . Thank you .
Uh , well - well , yes .
My wife 's alone at the — at the cottage .
We 've only got our manservant to look after her .
And I 'd be very grateful if you 'd call on her .
It 's only seven or eight miles up the trail . You can 't miss it .
Well , I 'll see you later .
[ wind howling ]
[ engine starts ]
- [ groaning ] - [ insects buzzing ]
[ groaning continues ]
Doctor , I thought it was more advisable to bring him here .
[ groaning ]
You did right .
What happened to your arm , Fritz ?
One of the living dead .
[ chuckles ] Too late .
I saw it too late .
Where ? Where did you see this ?
[ groans ] In the village —
[ groans ] I saw it .
- Oh . Oh , my God . - In this village ?
Ja .
- Tell Lucas to lock all the doors . - It 's no use .
It 's a waste of time to lock the doors .
They 'll be here soon ...
to destroy us all .
[ wind howling ]
[ Susan ] We must have driven eight miles by now .
Yes , more than that .
Why don 't we just take a chance
and sail for the nearest place where we know there 's a shipyard .
- After we 've seen the doctor 's wife . - Look , Peter . Is that it ?
[ whistles ] Nice layout .
Ah , the doctor 's doing all right by the look of it .
Yeah , but there 's something fishy about him .
[ knocking ]
Mrs. Menard !
Mrs. Menard ?
It doesn 't seem like anybody 's at home . What do we do now ?
Might as well go inside .
Is there anybody here ?
[ screams ]
On .
[ whimpering ]
[ low growl ]
Aah !
[ gasps ]
- Come on ! Come on ! - Get out of here ! Come on !
[ Peter ] Brian , you drive !
Quick , Brian ! Hurry !
- Get us out of here , please ! Get us out ! - [ engine starts ]
My God ! Did my father become one of those ?
No , he didn 't , Anne . You heard the doctor .
Let 's just find that hospital and get the hell out of here as quickly as we can .
[ wind howling ]
[ sighs ]
[ gunshot ]
Hey , look out !
[ groaning ]
Damn it .
[ clanking ]
[ steam hissing ]
The radiator 's had it .
Yeah , well , I think my ankle has gone the same way .
Great . We 're gonna have to walk now . You think you can make it ?
We don 't have much choice , do we ?
Well , come on . Let 's get to that hospital before dark .
- [ drumming in distance ] - [ natives chanting in distance ]
Drums .
Getting closer .
I hate it ! Damn you , you bastards ! [ panting ]
I can 't take it ! [ sobbing ]
Come on . They 're laying a little voodoo on us .
It 's got a sound all of its own .
Yes . Well , anyway , let 's hurry up .
It 's gonna be dark soon .
- [ drumming continues ] - [ chanting continues ]
- [ drumming continues in distance ] - [ wind howling ]
Lucas ?
You know what is the cause of all this ?
Is it voodoo ?
Lucas not know nothing , man .
The father — My father always say ...
when the earth spit out the dead ,
they will come back to suck the blood from the living .
That 's nonsense . That 's just a stupid superstition .
Yes , you are right , Doctor . You know many more things than Lucas .
I don 't believe that voodoo can bring the dead back to life .
And Lucas not believe ... that the dead be dead .
- [ drumming continues in distance ] - [ Peter grunting , groaning ]
No , it 's no good . I-I can 't go any further .
I gotta rest up for a bit .
Okay , Peter . We 'll take a quick five here .
We 've got to be close to that damn hospital now .
Look , why don 't you two rest here , and we 'll take a look up ahead , right ?
[ grunts ]
[ birds twittering ]
Hey , how about this ?
- What is it ? - It 's a helmet .
It must be all of 400 years old .
- [ drumming intensifies ] - [ chanting continues ]
This must have been a cemetery for the Spanish conquistadores .
- Ohh . - Thanks .
I 'm sorry I dragged you into all this .
It 's my father we came looking for , isn 't it ?
You know , when we get back to New York —
Uh-uh . You don 't have to say anything now .
It 's just ...
I 'm so scared we 're not gonna make it off this island .
[ low growl ]
[ screams ]
Ow ! [ grunting ]
[ bones cracking ]
[ screaming continues ]
- [ rustling ] - [ low growl ]
[ Anne screaming ]
[ screaming ]
[ gurgling ]
Susan .
- Susan . - [ grunts ]
Come on . Let 's go , before it 's too late .
- We can 't leave her here all alone . - She 's dead .
Brian , don 't you understand ? She 's dead .
Look , there 's nothing that you can do here .
Come on , man . Let 's go .
[ low growl ]
[ wind howling ]
- Ohh ! - Brian !
- It 's no good . I can 't — - You can 't stay here .
- Leave me here . - Come on . Get up .
- Oh , no ! They 're coming . - Save yourselves . Just leave me .
- Get up ! - Man , you can make it .
- Ohh . - Come on . I 've got you .
[ Brian ] That the church ? The doctor 's hospital . We 've done it .
Come on , man . Come on , Peter .
We 've done it .
[ insects buzzing ]
He 's fading rapidly .
Shall I continue with the transfusion ?
No , it 's useless . He 's gonna die anyway .
- [ pounding ] - [ Brian ] Dr. Menard !
[ Anne ] They 're right behind us ! Open the door !
[ pounding continues ]
[ Brian ] Come on , Doctor ! Open the damn door !
[ Anne ] Doctor , open up !
- [ Brian ] Dr. Menard ! For Christ 's sake ! - [ pounding ]
- [ Brian ] What took you so long ? - Oh , thank God !
Out there , they 're coming back to life . They 're everywhere !
[ wind howling ]
- [ banging ] - [ insects buzzing ]
[ buzzing continues ]
[ groans ]
What about my wife ?
Thank you .
[ grunting ]
What the hell are they , Doctor ?
I don 't know .
[ insects buzzing ]
It all started about three months ago .
One of the fishermen said he 'd seen his wife walking in the village at night .
Only she 'd been dead for two days .
Well , at the time , nobody believed the story .
[ chuckles ] In these islands , fantastic legends ...
voodooism , zombies ...
have been rife for centuries .
[ wind howling ]
- [ drumming in distance ] - [ natives chanting in distance ]
[ Menard ] As a man of science , I don 't believe in voodooism .
But the phenomenon defies logical explanation .
I 've attempted to apply the disciplines of bacteriology ,
virology , even of radiology .
We 've performed tests —
Epilepsy and for catalepsy .
[ sighs ] Nothing fits !
[ banging ]
[ wind howling ]
[ banging continues ]
- Will that hold them ? What do you think ? - Not a chance .
- How can we stop them ? - Here . Take this .
I 've got another gun in my office .
There 's two — two drums of kerosene in the sacristy .
Right , Doc . You two stay where you are . Watch those windows .
[ banging continues ]
[ wind howling ]
Nurse , come with me .
We 've got to get some empty bottles . All you can find .
[ growling ]
[ screaming ]
[ screaming continues ]
[ sobs ]
[ bones crunching ]
[ body thuds ]
Dr. Menard . Dr. Menard .
[ low growl ]
[ screaming ]
[ flesh ripping ]
[ groaning ]
[ groaning continues ]
[ whimpers ]
[ whimpering continues ]
[ screaming ]
No !
No ! No !
[ wood creaking ]
[ nurse ] Oh . Ohh !
[ nurse moaning ]
No . No !
You bring some too . Come on !
[ whimpers ]
[ screams ]
[ banging ]
[ banging continues ]
Go get some more bottles .
[ screams ]
[ gunshots ]
[ gunshot ]
Brian , two more .
Let 's get out of here ! Go !
[ gasps ]
- [ screams ] - [ flesh ripping ]
[ screaming ]
Shoot her , West !
Shoot her ! What are you waiting for ?
Come on , Brian . Let 's get to the boat . You can make it .
[ explosion ]
[ boat clanking ]
Can 't we go any faster ?
The driveshaft could go any second .
We 'll make for San Cristóbal .
There 's a yard there that we can fix —
- What is it ? - Brian .
I feel so cold . So cold .
[ shivers ] I don 't want to become like —
Take me home , Peter .
Save me .
[ Brian shivering ]
[ stammering ] Susan . [ sobs ]
[ gasping ]
[ groaning ]
He 's dead .
What do we do now ?
Lock him in the bilge . Take him back with us to the States .
Someone there might be able to do something .
But we can 't risk it . You know what he might turn into .
Well , I 'll make sure that he 's safe .
We 've got to take him back with us .
He 's the only proof we 've got that this all happened .
And we will need proof unfortunately .
Otherwise , they 'll just think that we 're crazy .
I don 't care .
I feel dead myself .
Take the wheel .
[ clanking ]
Let 's see if we can find something more cheerful on the radio .
[ man on radio ] The latest news ...
The situation here in New York City since the discovery of the first zombie ,
ls getting worse by the hour .
There 's chaos in the streets .
The National Guard cannot control the situation .
In every borough of the city ,
from Brooklyn to Manhattan , from Harlem to Queens ,
the zombies are taking over .
[ rattling ]
The governor has declared a state of national emergency
and has asked the president for immediate assistance .
The zombies are everywhere . There seems to be no way to stop them .
- The city is at their mercy . - [ rattling continues ]
According to latest reports from police headquarters ...
- [ low growl ] - ... the inhuman creatures are gathering
and seem to be heading towards Central Park .
Barricades have been thrown up throughout Manhattan .
General Steiner of the National Guard says missiles will be used if necessary .
I 've just been informed that zombies have entered the building .
They 're at the door ! They 're coming in !
[ screaming ]
[ car horns blaring ]